Matthew Young

🗣 Foster City, California 🗷 y.matt12@gmail.com 🗖 linkedin.com/in/matthew-young-07 🛎 matthewyoung777.gitlab.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Python, JavaScript, and Java. Skilled in back-end development using Node.js, Django, Fast API, and PostgreSQL, as well as front-end development with React.js. Experienced in system design using Docker and microservices.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: JavaScript, Python, Java, Django, Fast API, Docker, React.js, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Gitlab, Heroku Industry Knowledge: Agile Methodologies, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Unit Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Analysis, Data Science Interpersonal Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Problem solving, Adaptability, Quick Learning, Leadership

EXPERIENCE

Back-end Software Engineer

Fithub

September 2023 - Present, San Francisco Bay Area, CA

- · Conducted competitive analysis of market leading alternatives to drive feature selection and product differentiation.
- · Designed data model architecture for a MongoDB database for improved API response times up to 100ms.
- · Implemented a RESTful API using Node.js to extract and update data in a MongoDB database.

Software Engineer Intern

Networky.ai

October 2023 - Present, Palo Alto, CA

- · Ensured quality of the training data set for Machine Learning models, by reducing the amount of missing data from 50% to 20% for the training set.
- · Built pipeline integrating transactional text message notifications for e-commerce platform to increase user feedback by 40%.
- · Developed a backend API integrating CrunchBase API to populate training data and drive recommendation algorithm.

Autonomous Vehicle Test Specialist

Cruise

July 2021 - July 2022, San Francisco, CA

- · Increased drivable testing zones by 50% through lane and route mapping techniques.
- · Pinpointed and communicated problematic drive behavior data with engineers to reduce driving error frequency by 30%.
- $\cdot \text{ Trained fleet operators introducing new techniques for vehicle testing which increased driverless mileage accumulation by 100\%.}$

PROJECTS

Paper Stonks

Hackreactor · https://gitlab.com/apex-legends1/paper-stonks · October 2022 - December 2022

- · Developed a web-based mock stock trading application simulating investment portfolios and stock trading using real-time stock price data.
- · Orchestrated the creation of a highly scalable and secure REST API powered by Fast API to facilitate seamless data access.
- · Crafted engaging and interactive user interfaces using React.js, integrated with real-time stock data visualization through Chart.js.
- · Spearheaded the implementation of Docker-based microservice architectures for efficient deployment and scalability.
- · Developed GitLab CI/CD automation pipeline while leading a 5-member team to meet project goals.

Car Car

 $Hackreactor \cdot https://gitlab.com/matthewyoung 777/project-beta \cdot September 2022 - October 2022$

- Engineered a web app streamlining interactions between a dealership and its clientele, inventory tracking, vehicle sales, service appointments.
- · Crafted a dynamic and user-friendly front-end UI with React.js, focusing on the appointment microservice for enhanced user engagement.
- · Implemented a robust RESTful API for seamless data access within the appointment microservice with Django.
- $\cdot \ Held \ Scrum \ of scrums for \ discussing \ daily \ progress \ and \ sprint \ goals \ amongst \ the \ team, \ collaborating \ with \ Git \ version \ control.$
- · Designed and executed a scalable data model and microservices structure, with Django and Docker for performance and deployment efficiency.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

Hack Reactor · San Francisco, CA · November 2022

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Economics

University of Washington · Seattle, WA · 2019

 \cdot Dean's List recognition for 7 quarters

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL for Data Science

Coursera · 2019